<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AOE OpenSource</title><link>https://aoepeople.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on AOE OpenSource</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aoepeople.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Loving Open Source</title><link>https://aoepeople.github.io/posts/loving-open-source/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aoepeople.github.io/posts/loving-open-source/</guid><description>&lt;p>At AOE our most valuable asset is our experience with building complex enterprise applications to shape companies digital transformation, so why do we care about Open Source at all?
We grow by learning on new impulses, not by locking ourselves into our comfort zone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tailwind pushing us forward</title><link>https://aoepeople.github.io/posts/tailwind-pushing-forward/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aoepeople.github.io/posts/tailwind-pushing-forward/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are few technologies changing so often like web frontend tools, libraries and technologies in the recent years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With a focus on web development at AOE we have been on the bleeding edge ever since, evaluating and understading what technologies bring us forward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The weekly Dev-Weekly</title><link>https://aoepeople.github.io/posts/the-weekly-dev-weekly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aoepeople.github.io/posts/the-weekly-dev-weekly/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sharing knowledge and experience is what we love, but it took us a long time to establish a format where interested people come together on a regular basis, talking about newest tech, all cross-team and cross-project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Key to Keycloak</title><link>https://aoepeople.github.io/posts/key-to-keycloak/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aoepeople.github.io/posts/key-to-keycloak/</guid><description>&lt;p>Keycloak is our go-to tool when it comes to identity management, federating identities over multiple sources and organizing and managing roles for all kinds of applications.
Naturally, there is no &amp;ldquo;one-tool-fits-all&amp;rdquo;, so Keycloak too sometimes needs to be customized beyond what the configuration offers, and we need to implement providers to add additional configuration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Running (faster) with Gitlab CI</title><link>https://aoepeople.github.io/posts/running-gitlab-ci/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aoepeople.github.io/posts/running-gitlab-ci/</guid><description>Gitlab became our main tool for sourcecode and automation over the past 5 years. Naturally, all of our build processes, continous integration and delivery as well as platform management is completely automated, and Gitlab CI has proven to be a valuable tool.
So how do we organize our pipelines at AOE?
Initially, we have a repo which provides templates and starting points for all of our pipelines, so we can benefit from scaling to any number of microservices without having to think of management overhead.</description></item><item><title>Raising Flamingo(s)</title><link>https://aoepeople.github.io/posts/raising-flamingos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aoepeople.github.io/posts/raising-flamingos/</guid><description>&lt;p>5 years ago we set started the adoption of the Go programming language at AOE. 3 years ago we open sourced Flamingo, our web framework, created to enable us to build fast and scalable applications.
Now, looking back, it was quite a ride raising a flock of small Flamingo&amp;rsquo;s to form a stable basis for our daily work.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>